## **UDDIP RANJAN DAS**

New Delhi, India ·+91 9311237276

Email · LinkedIn · Twitter · Website

Information Security Specialist with passion for aligning security architecture plans and processes with security standards and business goals. A security researcher who's interested in malware research, threat intelligence. Also, a hardware enthusiast, pianist and a dog lover<3

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# MARCH 2022 – PRESENT SOC ANALYST, VERSPRITE CYBERSECURITY

- Monitoring and managing vSOC
- Malware research and CTI

### DECEMBER 2021 – FEBURARY 2022 SECURITY RESEARCH INTERN, VERSPRITE CYBERSECURITY

- Malware research
- Threat hunting
- Windows Internals & VR

## AUGUST 2021 – DECEMBER 2021 SECURITY RESEARCHER, MINISTRY OF DEFENCE OF INDIA

# **DECEMBER 2019 – JULY 2020 INFORMATION SECURITY ANALYST, INNEFU LABS PVT. LTD.**

- Provided safety reports and data analysis to building managers to inform security processes
- Completed vulnerability scans to identify at-risk systems and remediate issues
- Performed risk analyses to identify appropriate security countermeasures
- Developed plans to safeguard computer files against modification, destruction or disclosure

## JULY 2018 – JULY 2019 INFORMATION SECURITY TRAINEE, INNOBUZZ KNOWLEDGE SOLUTIONS

- Taught Students about Penetration testing and Web Application Security
- Perform regular audits to ensure security practices are compliant

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BACHELOR IN COMPUTER APPLICATIONS (2018 – 2022)**

INDIRA GANDHI NATIONAL OPEN UNIVERSITY, NEW DELH

#### **BACHELOR OF ARTS**

SUBHARTI UNIVERSITY, NEW DELH (2020-2023)

12<sup>TH</sup> CLASS - CBSE BOARD - 76% (2016-2017)

INDIRAPURAM PUBLIC SCHOOL, GHAZIABAD

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Certified Red Team Professional (Pentester Academy)
- Advanced Diploma in Information Security (Innobuzz Knowledge Solutions)

#### SKILLS SETS

- Malware Analysis
- Reverse Engineering
- Windows Internals
- Threat Intel & Hunting
- Penetration Testing & Active Directory
- Red Teaming & Social Engineering
- MITRE ATT&CK Framework

## **ACTIVITIES**

Currently a member of PolyX as a community malware researcher.

- Identify and use tools and techniques to conduct static and dynamic analysis of malware, including building a lab environment
- Working knowledge of file formats such as PE, PDF, etc.
- Working knowledge of IDA Pro/Debuggers
- Working knowledge of dynamic/static malware analysis
- Basic knowledge of Windows Operating System Internals (Kernel; Registry; File system; Windows APIs)
- Basic WinDbg Knowledge
- Able to read, debug and analyze disassembly of x86 and x64 binaries

Participated in Operation Chimera organized by Security Blue Team.

Try Hack Me – top 1% rankings

Hack The Box - Hacker Rank

### **TRAININGS**

- 101 Reverse Engineering Public Version by U.S. Department of Homeland Security
- Primer on Fuzzing and Exploit Development by National Information Security Council
- Certificate Course in Cybersecurity by Amity Future Academy.
- Wild West Hack Fest's **SOC core skills Training.**
- ICSI | CNSS Certified Network Security Specialist by International Cybersecurity Institute.
- Autopsy Digital Forensics hands-on training by Basis Technology.
- Fortinet's certified **Network Security Expert**.
- Zero to One in Web Recon by National Information Security Council